-=The Last Fantasy=-
翻译:拉拉叫我爆爆，accnk，雪梨，juarez 校对:・岁月倒影・
It's a beautiful day, isn't it?
So far, but they're calling for storms later.
Well, you know the heartland, some things can change in a minute.
-Is everyone assembled? -Twenty-four hours isn't a lot of notice.
Will you give me a heads-up as to the nature of your remarks?
Just one of my customary motivational speeches you've heard hundreds of times.
-How are you? Good to see you. -How you doing?
-Good morning. Good to see you. -Good morning.
-Good morning. Good to see you. -Thank you.
Fire up the troops!
The plant made a profit this quarter for the first time in two years.
My people are expecting a pat on the back, and they deserve to get it.
I'll try not to disappoint them.
Thank you.
As most of you know...
...you've all worked extremely hard this past year...
...and you should all be proud of yourselves.
Just as a ship can only follow the course...
...set by its captain...
...any business is only as good as its leadership.
Due to management failures beyond your control...
...this plant will be closing...
...effective immediately.
Good luck to all of you.
You just fired 2500 people and blamed it on me.
One day you'll thank me. Smallville isn't in your future.
-It's just a brief chapter in your biography. -Don't do this.
We live in a meritocracy, Lex. The weak get left behind.
The plant wasn't producing. I had no other options.
Spare me the corporate barbarian spiel.
Those people have husbands and wives, children, mortgages.
We're in business to make profits, not friends!
Don't let your emotions get in the way of making tough decisions!
Don't lecture me about letting emotions get in the way.
This plant was showing a profit.
You're shutting it down because I wouldn't go work for you in Metropolis.
Lex, you may have felt that you found a home here, but you were mistaken.
This was just your training ground. Well, your training is over!
You're coming home, son!
片名:超人前传
主题曲《Save me》:谁来拯救我
领衔主演：汤姆・威灵
让你温暖的手伸出驱散我的痛苦
主演:克丽斯汀・克鲁克
谁来拯救我
主演:迈克尔・罗森巴姆
我不在乎你是怎么做到
主演：埃里克・约翰森
只要你留下，和我在一起
主演：山姆・琼斯三世
快来吧，我一直在等待着你
主演：艾利森・麦克
主演：安妮特・奥图尔
约翰・施耐得 饰演 强纳森・肯特
我一直留着整个世界只为你闪耀
超人始创作者:杰瑞・希杰尔和乔・夏斯特
留下，留下
快出现吧
电视策划:阿尔弗雷德・哥夫，麦尔斯・米莱
第二十一集:暴风
Pete, I need your opinion. Classic black or traditional red?
特别客串主演:约翰・格鲁夫
For what?
My tie-cummerbund combo. I gotta get my tux order in today.
客串主演:罗伯特・韦斯顿
If I were you, I'd stick with the traditional black.
-This is no time to get adventurous. -You're right.
I don't know, Clark. Red always looks good on you.
Then red it is.
Thanks. Now I gotta go make a call and change my order.
I don't want people mistaking us for twins.
联合执行制片:格列哥・比曼
Yeah, because that happens all the time.
You seem really excited about the dance.
监督制片:马克・伏黑顿
I am, but between the tickets, the tux and buying the flowers, it gets expensive.
制片:迈克尔・格林
You should try finding the right dress.
Guess the limo's out.
制片:道里斯・伊根
I'm actually thinking of asking Lex if I can borrow his.
联合制片:格雷格・沃克
Chloe says she doesn't care, but deep down I know she wants one.
I'm trying to surprise her, so keep it between us.
My lips are sealed.
Chloe?
They're closing the LuthorCorp plant.
制片人:鲍勃・哈格罗夫
-So you heard. -The Ledger rushed a special edition.
They haven't done that since the meteor shower.
I talked to Chloe. She's pretty upset.
I spoke to her father. He's in shock.
I don't blame him.
联合执行制片:肯・霍顿
-How's this gonna affect us? -That plant was Smallville's biggest employer.
剧本:阿尔弗雷德・哥夫，麦尔斯・米莱
Shutting it down is gonna have a domino effect.
I can't believe Lex would run it into the ground in less than a year.
故事:菲利普・莱温斯
Why are you blaming Lex? His dad closed the plant.
Whatever issues Lionel Luthor has with his son have now cost half the town their jobs.
You should be happy, then. It means Lex is going back to Metropolis and out of our lives.
The plant closing is gonna hurt a lot of people, Clark.
As much as I would like Lex out of our lives, I wouldn't wish that on anybody.
导演:格列哥・比曼
（卢瑟公司农工厂关闭，管理不善）
天气真好呀
现在是，但稍后会有暴风雨
内陆嘛，瞬息万变
- 大家都到齐了吗? - 二十四小时集合还是有点急了
能给点有关你演讲的提示吗？
就是惯例性质的激励演讲，你都听过几百遍了
- 你好吗，很高兴见到你 - 你好吗？
- 早上好，很高兴见到你 - 早上好
- 早上好，很高兴见到你 - 谢谢
我们团队加油！
本季度是这个工厂在两年来首次盈利
我的人都期待有所奖励，这也是他们应得的
我尽量不让他们失望
谢谢
你们大都知道…
…这一年来大家工作极其努力…
…你们都应该感到自豪
就像一艘船只能跟着…
…船长设定的路线…
…所有事业都关乎其领导
由于管理失败已经不是各位能控制的了…
…这间工厂将会关闭…
…即时生效
祝君好运
你刚刚让2500人失业了，而且还归罪于我
总有一天你会感激我的，你的未来不在这里
- 这只是你人生的开篇 - 别这样
我们生活在精英统治的世界，莱克斯，优胜劣汰
工厂没有生产力，我别无选择
少跟我来那套
那些人上有老下有小
做生意只看利益，不讲人情
不要优柔寡断！
别教训我感情用事
这间工厂是有利润的
你关闭工厂只是因为我不跟你去大都会工作
莱克斯，你可能把这里当成家，但你错了
你只是在这里锻炼锻炼的，而现在大限已到！
你得回家了，儿子！
皮特，给点意见，经典黑还是传统红？
配什么?
我的小礼服，今天就送到了
我是你的话，我会坚持传统黑
- 这时候还是保险点 - 你说得对
克拉克，这可不一定哦 你穿红色一向很好看
那就红的吧
谢了，现在我得打个电话改一下我那件
我可不想人们误以为我们是双胞胎
就是，咱俩那么容易被误认哈
看样子你很待见那舞会
的确，但除了票价，礼服和买花都要花不少钱
你最好找条合适的礼服
看来豪华轿车是没了
我在想是否要向莱克斯借
克洛伊说无所谓，但她内心还是会想要的
我想给她个惊喜，所以就你知我知
我嘴很严的
克洛伊？
他们要关闭卢瑟农工厂了
- 你们也听说了 - 分类报紧急出了特刊
自从流星雨事件后就没再出过特刊
我跟克罗伊谈过了，她特沮丧
我和她父亲说了，他很震惊
我不怪他
- 这对我们会有什么影响? - 那间工厂是镇上最大的雇主
工厂倒闭将会产生多米诺效应
我没想到，不到一年，莱克斯就把它毁了
你干嘛要怪莱克斯？他老爸关的厂
老卢瑟和他儿子的矛盾害镇上一半人丢了工作
那你该高兴才是，这样莱克斯就会回大都会 离开我们的视线
克拉克，工厂倒闭会伤害很多人的
虽然我很想让莱克斯滚蛋，但我也不想害到人
我知道的，爸爸，只不过莱克斯在乎这个镇
I know, Dad. It's just.... Lex cares about the town.
他有大抱负
He said he had big plans.
下地狱的路也是由好心铺成的
The road to hell is paved with good intentions.
好了，转弯，就快到了
Okay. Turn. We're almost there.
好了
All right.
- 好 - 停
-Okay. -Stop.
张开眼睛
Open your eyes.
哇！
Wow!
你干嘛要神秘兮兮的？
Why are you being so mysterious?
- 我就不能给女朋友准备个意外野餐? - 我又没抱怨
-Can't a guy plan a picnic for his girlfriend? -I'm not complaining.
只是有点意外
It's just kind of spontaneous.
你是在说我平时很无聊吗？
Are you saying I'm usually boring?
我是说你太好了，好奇今儿什么日子
I'm saying this is very nice. I'm just wondering what the occasion is.
就是要感谢你做过的一切
It's to thank you for everything.
今年很坎坷，多谢你一路支持
It's been a difficult year, and you've stood by me.
我曾将你推开，而你 本可以另觅他人，但你没有
I pushed you away, and you could have made other choices. You didn't.
我们一起很长时间了 我不会在你需要我的时候离开
We've been together a long time. I'd never abandon you when you needed me.
我有件事要告诉你
There's something I want to tell you.
惠特尼，你知道，也许我们可以…
Whitney, you know, maybe we should--
- 这是什么？ - 读读
-What's this? -Read it.
美国海军陆战队？
United States Marine Corps?
我参军了
I enlisted.
我想这是我该做的
I think it's the right thing for me to do.
当我发现父亲的勋章时，我感觉他在指引我
When I found my dad's medals, I felt he was telling me which path I should take.
- 你不能为了你父亲就入伍 - 我没有，这是为了我们
-You can't do this for your father. -I'm not. I'm doing it for us.
求你别生气
Please, don't be mad.
事情发生太快了，你知道吗？
It's just so fast, you know?
我需要点时间来消化
I need some time to process it.
我没多少时间了
I don't have a lot of time.
周六晚我就得出海做基础训练了
I ship out for basic training Saturday night.
那毕业典礼呢？
What about graduation?
镇上唯一让我牵挂的就只有你了
The only thing I'm gonna miss in Smallville is you.
你会等我吗？
Will you wait for me?
克拉克，我收到你的消息了 但我今天很糟糕
Clark, I got your messages, but I've been having a bad day.
镇纸不错
Nice paperweight.
对，很特别
Yeah, very unique.
你不怕被人看到和我这败家子在一起吗?
Sure you can afford being seen with the town pariah?
我愿意冒这个险
I'll take my chances.
莱克斯，发生什么事了？
What happened, Lex?
现在有两个说法…
The two theories seem to be...
…一是我很无能，把工厂毁了…
...I either ran the plant into the ground through incompetence...
…二是我为了回大都会，故意为之
...or did it deliberately to go back to Metropolis.
你爸早就让你去那边工作了，你说出事实就好
Your dad already offered you a job in Metropolis. Just tell people the truth.
那我就是无能了
Then I get stuck with the incompetence rap.
还不如被世人责骂
Being reviled is the lesser evil.
那你就是要回去大都会了
I guess you're going back to Metropolis, then.
我爸爸设这个局就是为了这个 但是这还不算完
That's why my father orchestrated his coup, but this isn't over.
- 你还有什么计划？ - 差不多吧
-You have a plan? -Maybe.
你先忙，不打扰你了
You have a lot of work to do.
克拉克，谢谢你能过来看我 这对我很重要
Clark, thanks for stopping by. It means a lot.
交朋友是为了什么啊？
What are friends for?
就知道可以在这儿找到你
Thought I'd find you here.
我爸爸和我无法共同面对这种灾难，所以…
My dad and I can't really do the whole depressed thing together, so....
如果你不想参加周六晚会，我能理解的
If you're not up for Saturday night, I'd understand.
开什么玩笑？那是我现在唯一期待的事情了
You kidding me? It's the only thing I have to look forward to right now.
还有就是，趁我还没走， 我很想再享受下斯摩维尔古怪有趣的风俗
Besides, I want to enjoy all the quaint Smallville High customs while I still can.
什么？你要去哪儿？
Why? Where are you going?
我爸爸正考虑搬回大都会定居
My dad's talking about moving us back to Metropolis permanently.
那《火炬报》，还有你的朋友呢？
What about the Torch and all your friends?
我现在还没时间考虑这些
I can't even think about it right now.
克拉克，我也不想再那么辛苦
Clark, I'm not exactly psyched about having to fight my way...
到新的高中再经营一次
...through the high school hierarchy all over again.
你会想我的，对吧？
You're gonna miss me, right?
这还用问？
Do you even have to ask?
答应我，周六晚上会很精彩
Just promise me Saturday night's gonna be great.
那将会是一个你永生难忘的夜晚
It'll be a night you won't forget.
很高兴你们能来
I appreciate you coming.
我父亲还不知道这次会议 而且我也不希望他知道
My father doesn't know about this meeting, and I'd like to keep it that way.
当我初来乍到时…
When I first came here...
…人们可能会觉得 我可能又是一个典型的纨绔子弟
...people assumed I was just another glaring example of nepotism...
…没有本事，通过裙带关系不断晋升的人
...unskilled and promoted over the heads of the more competent and deserving.
但我想让这屋里的人对我刮目相看
But I'd like to think the people in this room feel differently.
如果我们能够筹集到资金， 让所有员工买断股份的话…
If we can raise the capital for an employee-led buyout...
- 我们可以让农工厂继续经营下去的 - 买断？
-...we can keep the plant running. -Buyout?
我可以筹集将近90%的资金
I can raise nearly 90%% of the capital.
剩下的怎么办？ 我们得抵押房产吗
What about the rest? We're supposed to mortgage our houses?
的确有风险，我明白
It's a risk, I know.
但好处是，我们能让那些投资人成为少数派了
But in exchange, the investors will become minority owners.
你父亲不是控制着董事会么？ 他会同意买断么？
Doesn't your father control the board? Why would he go along with a buyout?
我认识一些董事会的成员，我可以说服他们 并且不需要他们全部都通过
I know a couple of members I can convince, and I don't need a unanimous decision.
现在摆在你们面前的是一个能够决定 你们自己命运的机会
I'm offering you the chance to take control of your own destiny.
支持我，我们会赢的
Stand with me, and we'll win.
克拉克
Clark.
（斯摩维尔镇最好的卡布奇诺）
这么好性质出来逛街？
Out wandering the streets of Smallville?
怎么了？
What is it?
我刚听说克罗伊要搬走了
I just found out that Chloe might be leaving for good.
真不敢相信这是真的
Not sure I really believe it's true.
我理解你的感受
I know what you mean.
什么，你理解？
You do?
惠特尼也要入伍参加海军去了
Whitney's going off to join the Marines.
这太扯了
That's intense.
他告诉我这么做是为了我们俩
He told me he was doing it for us.
问我是否愿意等他
Asked if I'd wait for him.
真的吗？那你怎么说？
Really? What did you say?
什么也没说
Nothing.
我只是傻傻站在那儿，很吃惊，什么也没说
I kind of just stood there in stunned silence.
前阵子他还说他担心他的英文论文
One day he's worried about his English paper...
紧接着他却要穿上制服，拯救世界去了
...and the next, he's putting on a uniform and saving the world.
那你没给他什么承诺么？
So you didn't commit?
我告诉他我不确定
I told him I wasn't sure.
他什么时候出发？
When does he head out?
周六晚上
Saturday night.
这下你倒是不用发愁礼服的事了
Guess you don't have to worry about your dress.
真不敢相信，惠特尼和克罗伊都要离开我们
I can't believe both Whitney and Chloe are gonna be out of our lives.
我也是
Me neither.
我想我们被甩了，克拉克
Guess we get left behind, Clark.
你觉得是什么引发爆炸的？
What do you think caused the explosion?
儿子，我想可能是油管漏油吧
Son, my guess is it was a leaky fuel line.
火苗引燃了车上的肥料，我应该再仔细检查下
The fumes must have ignited the fertilizer in the truck. I should have checked it better.
- 庆幸的是，车上是我，不是你们二老 - 哦，真是我的好儿子
-I'm glad it was me and not one of you guys. -Oh, sweetheart.
奇怪的是，这次我没有一点灼烧感
The truth is, I barely felt the heat this time.
并且爆炸碎片也没有造成任何瘀伤
And the debris didn't leave any bruises.
随着年龄的增长 你的身体肯定变得越来越强壮
As you get older, your body must be getting stronger.
（你可以选择…）
你还不赶紧收拾东西？
You're not in a hurry to pack?
我就没打算走
That's because I'm not leaving.
接受命运吧，莱克斯
Accept your fate, Lex. It's time to move on.
我设法使主管委员会投票 让他们接受员工对农场的股权买断
I'm forcing a vote of the board of directors to accept an employee buyout of the plant.
你要干嘛？说服员工们进行二次抵押？
What are you gonna do? Convince the employees to take out a second mortgage?
- 利用他们的退休金 - 差不多就那个意思吧
-Cash in their IRAs. -Something like that.
即使你卖掉所有股票，耗尽你的信托基金
Even if you sell all your stock and drain your trust fund...
还是不够，莱克斯
...you still come up short, Lex.
不够的钱你打算怎么办呢？
What will you do about the rest of the money?
现在接受股权买断，你还能保持你的尊严
Take the buyout now, and you can keep your dignity.
- 这可比你留给我的多多了 - 可真是我的好儿子啊
-That's more than you left me. -That's very gracious of you, son.
你先不妨看看这个
You might wanna look at this first.
你已经买下了斯摩维尔储贷银行
You've bought the Smallville Savings and Loan.
继续，继续你的购买计划 但是记住了，我掌握着你员工的抵押房屋
Go ahead, lead your buyout. But remember, I own your employees' mortgages.
一旦他们欠了一点还款
As soon as they begin missing payments...
我会毫不犹豫地取消他们的赎回权
...I won't hesitate to foreclose on each and every one of them.
到时候他们就会无家可归 然后这一切都会归咎到你头上
They'll be homeless, and it will be your fault.
你有准备承担那样的责任么？
You ready to accept that kind of responsibility?
如果你胆敢跟我作对的话，儿子
If you're going to take me on, son...
你得拿出真本事才行
...you're gonna have to bring your game up to a whole different level.
- 克罗伊，你去哪儿了？ - 我正打算去取我的礼服呢
-Where have you been? -I went to pick up my dress.
- 我们有麻烦了 - 你不能参加了？
-We have a problem. -You can't go.
没有，只是不能接你了，我的车子被烧了
I just can't pick you up. My transportation kind of went up in flames.
我本打算问莱克斯，能不能借他的轿车来用 但是农工厂的事儿…
I was gonna ask Lex if I could borrow his limo, but with the plant--
- 克拉克，那就我来开好了 - 抱歉破坏了王子的美好形象
-Clark, I'll drive. -Ruins the whole Prince Charming vibe.
我也不是什么灰姑娘啊
Cinderella was never my role model.
- 为什么要当海军啊？ - 不知道，只是觉得自己该去
-Why the Marines? -I don't know. It's just something I gotta do.
- 惠特尼要去为山姆大叔打仗了 - 我听说了
-So Whitney's off to fight evil for Uncle Sam. -I heard.
那样的话拉娜岂不是又名花无主了
That technically makes Lana a free agent.
他请求她等他
He asked her to wait for him.
异地恋很难坚持下去的
Long-distance relationships never work.
人会变的，经历也不一样了 有点和我们类似，对吧？
People change, have different experiences. It's kind of like us, you know?
过不多久，你就会把我忘得一干二净的
After a couple of weeks, you'll forget all about me.
克罗伊，说什么呢！
Chloe!
好吧，我只是做了个噩梦
Okay, I just have this horrible nightmare...
梦见惠特尼前脚刚走，你就迫不及待跑到车站
...that you'll rush to the bus station after Whitney leaves...
然后向拉娜表白你永恒的爱意 剩下我一个人孤零零在体育馆等着
...and profess your undying love for Lana, and I'll be waiting at the gym alone.
如果你胆敢那样对我，克拉克 我永远都不会再搭理你
If you do that to me, Clark, I'll never speak to you again.
好了，我说完了
Okay, I said it.
克罗伊
Chloe.
我要和你一起跳舞，不是为别的 是我自己想要这样
I'm going to the dance with you not by default, but because I want to.
很好，我现在感觉好多了
All right, I feel better now.
（恭喜毕业，然后怎样？）
我能耽误你一分钟时间么，克拉克
If I could just have one minute of your time, Clark.
- 你怎么会知道我的名字？ - 我是罗杰・尼克松
-How do you know my name? -Roger Nixon.
我是询察报的记者，我很想写篇有关你的报道
I'm a journalist with the Inquisitor, and I would like to write a story about you.
谢谢，但是我不感兴趣
Thanks, but I'm really not interested.
你为何能在爆炸中不受伤？
Why weren't you hurt in that explosion?
你当时的确是在农场里的卡车上
You were in the truck on the farm.
我根本不在卡车附近
I was nowhere near that truck.
我是不是错过什么有意思的事了？
Am I missing something interesting?
莱克斯？
Lex?
你知道我名字，但我不知道你的
You know my name, but I don't know yours.
我叫罗杰・尼克松，我为询察报工作
Roger Nixon. I work for the Inquisitor.
你怎么和那种报纸同流合污啊？
When is someone gonna put that bad excuse for a tabloid out of its misery?
见到你很高兴，莱克斯
It was nice meeting you, Lex.
我们很快会再见面的，克拉克
I'm sure we'll talk again soon, Clark.
怎么回事
What was that all about?
他想在我身上挖掘些材料 使我成为某种英雄
He wants to do a story on me, make me out to be some kind of hero.
那报纸的人不是什么好东西，克拉克
The Inquisitor's a rag, Clark.
如果我是你，我不会和他混在一起
If I were you, I wouldn't get mixed up with him.
我也不想
I don't intend to.
如果他再找你麻烦，告诉我
If he gives you any more trouble, let me know.
嗨，儿子
Hi, son.
出什么事了？
Something wrong?
询察者的记者想写我的事
A journalist from the Inquisitor wants to do a story on me.
他知道我当时在卡车里
He knows I was in the truck.
我不认为那是意外，他在专门测试我
I don't think it was an accident. I think he set it up to test me.
他怎么知道你能死里逃生？
How did he know you would survive?
他以前一定见过我做别的事
He must have seen me do something before.
我发誓自从费兰的事以后 我已经很小心了
Look, I swear, ever since Phelan, I've been so careful.
克拉克，这不是你的错
Clark, it's not your fault.
- 但是我该怎么办？ - 一切照旧，去上学，参加舞会
-But what do I do? -Carry on, go to school, go to the dance...
如果这记者真有什么证据 他会来找我们的
...and if this reporter's really got something, I'm sure he'll come talk to us.
还有什么事？
What else?
我想莱克斯可能有我太空船的部分残骸
I think Lex has a piece of the spaceship.
你确定？
Are you sure?
我在他桌上见过，就是遗失的那块
I saw it on his desk. It's the missing piece.
他一定是在郊外捡到的
He must have found it in the field.
我不知道他是否起疑 但谁能知道他会做什么呢？
I don't know if he suspects anything, but who knows what he'll do?
- 我们都知道莱克斯是个追究到底的人… - 他不会想到是我们
-We all know how persistent Lex can be-- -He can't trace it to us.
你妈妈说得对，我们低调点就是了
Your mother's right, son. We'll just keep our heads low.
当你做日常事的时候，不要用你的超能
So when you do your chores, don't use your abilities.
不论做什么事 远离地下的避难室
Whatever you do, stay away from that storm cellar.
你想见我, 莱克斯？
You wanted to see me, Lex?
我很意外，你竟然记得我的名字
I'm surprised you even remembered my name.
我警告过你，离他家远点
I warned you to stay away from the Kents.
让我猜猜，到这就是想提醒我
Let me guess. This is where you remind me...
你能对我做的所有可怕的事
...of all the terrible things you can have done to me.
我知道你已经完全清楚我的意图 我现在比较忙
As I'm sure you're well aware, I'm a little preoccupied at the moment.
没时间处理你的不满
I don't have time to deal with your annoyances.
我的发现远远超过了你和你的问题
Well, what I have discovered is beyond you and your problems...
以及你的威胁
...and your threats.
这些自负对你不利, 罗杰
This newfound self-assurance doesn't suit you, Roger.
友好点, 莱克斯 要不然我就不会把我的发现卖给你了
Be nice, Lex, or I may not let you bid on my discovery.
我知道你想买
And I know you'll want to...
尤其它还是关于车祸现场和肯特一家
...especially when you consider all your interest in the crash site and the Kents.
在那发现的东西与你和肯特家都无关
What was found out there has nothing to do with the Kents or with you.
你确定？
Are you certain?
罗杰,你有种就提供证据
Roger, for all your bravado, you have yet to show me anything.
今晚我就可以提供
I'll show you all the evidence you need tonight.
你会亲眼看到
And you'll see for yourself.
这些关于你朋友克拉克・肯特的事 远远超过你所知道的
There's a whole lot more to your friend Clark Kent than meets the eye.
- 我发誓, 如果你再骚扰克拉克和他的父母… - 谁说要骚扰？
-I swear, if you harass Clark or his parents-- -Who said anything about harassment?
或许我要告诉他们真相，是你先要研究他们 我才会惹上他们的
Maybe I'll just tell them the truth, that you turned me on to them.
如果你对我掌握的这些不感兴趣 我认识另一个姓卢瑟的，他可能会感兴趣
And if you're not interested in what I have, I know of another Luthor who will be.
你在玩火
You are playing a very dangerous game.
你最好祈祷你没错
You'd better pray you're not wrong.
妈妈，可以帮我一下吗？
Mom, can you give me a hand with this?
谁在那？
Who's there?
是我, 克拉克，你好吗？
It's me, Clark. Are you all right?
- 耶，很好 - 真的，你看上去有些紧张
-Yeah, I'm fine. -Really? You seem a little tense.
是跳舞那些事
It's just the dance and everything.
过来
Come here.
相信我打领带比你妈妈打得还多
I'm sure I've tied more of these than your mother.
我以为你会宅在家里
Thought you were holed up in the mansion.
我需要清醒下头脑，开车就到这了
Well, I needed to clear my head. Took a drive, ended up here.
我不是想在你的大日子打扰你
I didn't mean to bother you on your big day.
我有时间，克罗伊要来接我
I got a little time. Chloe's picking me up.
进展可真快，你的车怎么了？
That's very progressive. What happened to the truck?
做农活时坏了，你知道怎么回事
A farming accident. You know how it is.
资金筹备得怎么样了？
So how goes the bailout?
不好说，克拉克，我想在变好之前一定会更糟
I'm not sure, Clark. I think it's gonna get ugly before it gets better.
我爸爸拼命都不会让我成功的
My father's dead set against me succeeding.
为什么你爸爸这么抵触你的工厂？
Why would your father be against the plant?
我们的关系很复杂，克拉克
We have a complicated relationship, Clark.
我爸爸想让我相信，父子关系要互相信任 事实上却不是
My father wants me to believe it's built on trust, but it's not.
我们的父子关系只建立在谎言和欺骗上
It's built on lies and deceit.
任何这样的关系都注定要失败
Any relationship with that foundation is destined to fail.
- 幸运的是我们没有这样的问题 - 是幸运
-Lucky we don't have that problem. -Lucky us.
我想让你知道无论接下来的日子发生了什么
I want you to know whatever happens in the next few days...
我依然是你的朋友，永不改变
...I'm still your friend, and that's never gonna change.
- 我希望你也是这么想的 - 是的啊
-I hope you feel the same way. -I do.
你认为会发生什么
What do you think's gonna happen?
不知道，就是有种不祥的感觉
I don't know. Just got a bad feeling...
就像暴风雨来临前空气的那股味道
...like when you can smell the air change before a storm.
暴风雨是常发生的,莱克斯
Storms are a way of life around here, Lex.
只要别被它阻在路上
The trick is to not get caught out in the open.
照顾好自己
Look after yourself.
（惠特尼・佛得曼 最有价值球队组员，2002年度）
简直难以置信，我一直认为 我的一生就要在这些辉煌的奖杯上
It's hard to believe. I thought my whole life was in that trophy case.
但现在看起来，它们是那么微不足道
Now it all seems so trivial.
我们该送你到车站了
We should get you to the bus station.
汽车一小时后才离开
My bus doesn't leave for an hour.
去看看体育馆怎么样？
How about we go check out the gym?
好的
Okay.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
他们呢？
Where is everyone?
一小时后舞会开始, 筹备委员会的人都回家准备了
Hour before the dance, the setup committee goes home to get ready.
你因我错过了这场春季舞会
You're missing the spring formal because of me.
我们仍然有时间跳最后一只舞
We still have time for one last dance.
对不起，我没有提前把入伍的事告诉你
I'm sorry I didn't tell you before I enlisted.
你真得很勇敢
I think you're very brave.
我知道这很突然  你还不再确定我们的关系
I know this is kind of sudden, and you're not sure how you feel about us--
惠特尼，就跳舞吧
Whitney, let's just dance.
嗨
Hi.
你觉得怎么样，太艳吗？
What do you think? Too pink?
不，你…你真美
No. You-- You look beautiful.
谢谢，你把自己打扮得也很帅气
Thank you. You clean up nicely yourself.
红色领带呢？
What happened to the red tie?
直觉告诉我那样是错的.
Instinct told me it was the wrong way to go.
- 这是给我的吗？ - 是的
-Is that for me? -Oh, yeah.
哇哦
Oh, wow!
太漂亮了
It's beautiful.
我也给你带了礼物！
Oh, I have yours!
好的
Okay.
我扎到你了吗？
Oh, did I get you?
我们该走了
We should go.
耶，我们走吧
Yeah. Well, here we go.
- 我来开门 - 好的
-I'll get the door. -Okay.
-谢谢，看起来快要来暴风雨了 -没错
-Thanks. Looks like a storm's coming. -Yeah.
- 坐好了？ - 好了
-In? -In.
- 这太疯狂了 - 我知道
-This is crazy! -I know.
- 你还好吗？ - 快走吧
-You okay? -Let's go.
快到里面去
Let's get inside!
哇哦，你们看上去很不错
Wow, you guys look great.
谢谢，有眼光嘛，这是仿名牌的礼服
Well, thank you, Ms. Rivers. It's faux Wang.
- 嗨 - 嗨，埃瑞卡
-Hi. -Hi, Erica.
克罗伊，你能不能…？
Hey, Chloe, could you--?
- 他想让你给我们拍张照 - 好，当然可以
-He wants you to take our picture. -Oh, yeah, sure.
我马上回来，我想他是为了证明 终于有这么一天了
I'll just be a sec. I think he wants proof that this night actually happened.
- 就这样吧 - 祝你好运，惠特尼
-Well, I guess this is it. -Good luck, Whitney.
拉娜，我能单独跟克拉克待一会吗？
Lana, can I have a minute alone with Clark?
当然，我去把车开过来
Sure. I'll bring the truck around.
谢谢
Thanks.
你我这一年过得很怪异
You and I have had a weird year.
我开始以为你想从我手里 偷走拉娜
I started out thinking you just wanted to steal Lana.
我不是为了找借口 但我确实做了一些不光彩的事
I'm not trying to make excuses, but I did some things I'm not proud of.
对不起，克拉克
I'm sorry, Clark.
我接受了
I appreciate that.
克拉克，我想问你一些事 就当帮个忙
Listen, Clark, there's something I wanna ask you, a favor.
可以
Okay.
拉娜现在对我们的关系 还不是很确定
Lana's not sure how she feels about our relationship right now.
但我很确定
But I am.
我需要你在我回来之前照顾她
I need you to look after her until I get back.
我真不知道要说什么
I really don't know what to say.
说可以
Say yes.
可以
Okay.
克拉克？
Clark?
我保证
I promise.
谢谢
Thanks.
祝你幸运
Good luck.
刚才怎么了？
What was that all about?
说些男人的事情 我有说过你今晚非常漂亮吗？
Just guy stuff. Have I told you how beautiful you look tonight?
有啊，但经常提醒我会更好
Yeah, but frequent reminders are always appreciated.
东西都拿了？
Do you have everything?
- 只让带一个包 - 看来我不适合当海军战士
-You're only allowed one bag. -I'd never make it as a Marine.
这个给你，会带来好运
I want you to have this for luck.
这次我不会弄丢了
I won't lose it this time.
再见，拉娜
Goodbye, Lana.
第一眼见到你时，我就爱上了你
I loved you the first moment that I saw you.
当我再见你时，我会仍然爱你
I'll still love you when I see you again.
哦，罗杰
Oh, Roger.
宝贝…
Baby...
…你肯定要变成一个有钱人了
...you are going to be filthy rich!
- 嘿 - 嘿，克罗伊过得很开心
-Hey. -Hey, Chloe's having a great time.
- 我答应给她一个难忘的夜晚 - 我很高兴你终于采取行动了
-I promised her a night she'd never forget. -I'm glad you finally stepped up.
是啊，我也很高兴
Yeah, me too.
- 嘿，我喜欢这些人 - 雷米零度线乐队！
-Hey, I like these guys. -Yeah. Remy Zero!
我喜欢这首歌
I love this song.
- 这是克罗伊最喜欢的歌 - 不然我为什么点它
-This is one of Chloe's favorite songs. -Why do you think I requested it?
你给力啊！
Now, that's what I'm talking about!
- 可以请你跳支舞吗？ - 当然
-May I have this dance? -Of course.
动物都关好了！ 我们也没什么能做的了！
The animals are all put away! There's nothing more we can do here!
- 我们得去地下的避难窖！ - 克拉克怎么办？
-We gotta get to the storm cellar! -What about Clark?
学校在镇子另一边！ 他会没事的！
The school's on the other side of town! He'll be fine!
肯特先生！
Mr. Kent!
- 你他妈的是谁？ - 罗杰・尼克松，询察报的…
-Who the hell are you? -Roger Nixon, Metropolis In--
你就是那个威胁克拉克的记者！
You're the reporter who threatened Clark!
- 别动手！ - 为什么不？他想杀我们儿子！
-Don't do anything! -Why not? He tried to kill our son.
- 是你引爆了那辆卡车吧？ - 我知道那样不会伤害到他
-Did you blow up that truck? -I knew it wouldn't hurt him.
别，求你了！
No, please!
- 谁派你来的？莱克斯・卢瑟？！ - 强纳森，求你！
-Who sent you? Lex Luthor?! -Jonathan, please!
- 是莱克斯・卢瑟吗？！ - 我不需要莱克斯・卢瑟指使
-Was it Lex Luthor?! -I don't need Lex Luthor.
- 我会告诉全世界你儿子的事！ - 你休想！
-I'll tell the entire world about your son! -You will not!
别，强…
No! Jon--
起来，快点！
Get up, come on!
强纳森，看！
Jonathan, look!
强纳森，有龙卷风！
Jonathan, the tornado!
但他知道了所有的事
But he knows everything!
- 我不会让他毁了我们家！ - 别！求你了！
-I will not let him destroy this family! -No! Please!
强纳森！
Jonathan!
克拉克・肯特，神秘男人 当我觉得已经了解你时，你又会让我震惊
Clark Kent, man of mystery. Just when I think I have you figured out, you surprise me.
- 怎么会？ - 因为这首歌，这件礼服…
-How's that? -The song, the tux...
…这个晚上
...tonight.
- 而且我一直在这 - 嗯，你还在
-And I'm still here. -Yeah, you are.
请停一下音乐 打扰各位一会
Stop the music, please. Excuse me for a second.
请大家听我说，谢谢
Can I have everyone's attention, please? Thank you.
国家气象局刚刚发布了龙卷风警报
The National Weather Service has just issued a tornado warning.
发现有三个龙卷风正往斯摩维尔袭来
Three funnels were spotted heading towards Smallville.
现在请大家冷静
Now, please, everyone, stay calm.
龙卷风将在城南着陆 为了大家的安全…
The twisters are gonna set down south of here, but for your own safety...
…谁都不允许离开体育馆
...no one will be allowed to leave the gym.
汽车站在城南，拉娜在那里
The bus station's south of town. Lana's there.
别担心，我相信她已经到家了
Don't worry. I'm sure she's home by now.
我来给她打个电话，你在这等我
You know what? I'll go call her on my cell, and you wait here.
克拉克？
Clark?
该死的，尼克松！
Damn you, Nixon!
你准备用你妈妈的股份 来资助你的收购
So you're using your mother's stock to fund the buyout.
这是你的秘密资金来源
That's your secret source.
我必须承认，这是一项大胆的举措 莱克斯，但是这没用
I must admit, it's a bold move, Lex, but it won't work.
- 你冒着龙卷风的危险来告诉我这个？ - 这是自杀，莱克斯
-You braved the weather to tell me that? -It's suicide, Lex.
你也许能拿回工厂 但你在拿自己工人的家庭做赌注
You may get the plant, but you're putting your employees' homes on the line.
也可能摧毁你自己的未来
Forfeiting your own future.
或者创造一个远离你掌控的新命运
Or forging a new destiny free from you.
你不是我的敌人，你是我儿子
You're not my enemy. You're my son.
我没看出两者有什么差别
I never saw the distinction.
亚历山大大帝快死的时候，他的将军问他…
When Alexander the Great was dying, his generals asked...
准备把他的帝国留给谁…
...who he would leave his empire to...
…他是否能任命一个继承人 一个能完整保留遗产…
...if he would appoint a successor who would keep the legacy intact...
并能避免一代代流血事件的人
...prevent generations of bloodshed.
他的回答很简单:“我将它留给强者”
His answer was simple: "I leave it to the strongest."
我相信这话意思是:“鼓动浩劫，随时开战”
I believe the term is, "Cry havoc and let slip the dogs of war."
我要埋葬你，以及斯摩维尔里 所有站在你那边的人
I'll bury you and everyone in Smallville who takes your side.
不！
No!
莱克斯！
Lex!
帮帮我，莱克斯！
Help me, Lex!
莱克斯！
Lex!
我动不了！
Can't move!
救救我！
Help me!
莱克斯！
Lex!
儿子，求你！
Son, please!
该死的！
Damn it!
克拉克！
Clark!
拉娜！
Lana!
克拉克！
Clark!
不！
No!
（待续）